Rob McGuire-Dale | rob.mcguiredale@gmail.com | (541) 250 - 0762

# >>> Summary

\_\_\_\_\_\_

My primary interests are open source, and web development.

My favorite technologies are JavaScript, Python, HTML 5, Linux, and Git.

I've worked for Boeing, the Open Source Lab, and the Portland Art Museum.

I have a bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Oregon State University.

#### >>> Skills

\_\_\_\_\_\_

#### Technical:

- JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone.js, JSON
- Python, Django, Bottle, CherryPy
- HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, LESS
- Linux, Git, Bash, ViM
- Java, PHP, Drupal

# Social:

- Leadership: Lead for an enterprise-wide collaborative coding project
- Coordination: Event coordinator for OSU's Linux User Group
- Adaptation: Studied abroad in San Miguel de Allende, GTO, Mexico
- Communication: Several years of Internet technical support experience

# >>> Work Experience

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# >>> The Boeing Company

Developer, Linux Sysadmin, Project Manager | June 2010 - Current

# GitLab Exploration Project:

Led a team of 15 people to create and manage a GitHub-like, collaborative coding service for 120+ users. Based on GitLab, Gitolite, and Nginx.

# Enterprise Search Web Frontend:

Primary developer of the web frontend for Boeing's internal, enterprise-wide search application handling more than 270,000 hits/day. Based on Bootstrap, Backbone.js, jQuery, and Wok.

# Web Analytics Service:

Created and managed a web analytics service for several enterprise-wide web applications handling more than 1.1 million hits/day. Based on Piwik, MySQL, and Nginx.

# Data Migration Bridge:

Designed and developed a multi-threaded Java application interfacing two major manufacturing/production engineering applications. Achieved a speedup of 6.5x over legacy systems, reducing an 13-hour nightly job to only 2 hours.

# Mainframe Java API:

Designed and developed a Java programmable interface library to an electrical-engineering mainframe application. Based on the IBM 3270 terminal emulator.

### Application Security Analysis:

Penetration tested and analyzed web and thick-client applications for information and computer security vulnerabilities.

# >>> The Open Source Lab

G. St. v. v. D. v. 1 v. v. 1 D. v. 2000 . T. v. 2011

Software Developer | Dec. 2008 - June 2011

# Ganeti Web Manager:

Key developer of Ganeti Web Manager, a web-based application for managing Google's Ganeti cluster-based virtual machines. Based on Python, Django, javaScript, jQuery, HTML, and CSS.

# Touchscreen:

Key developer and designer of Touchscreen, an interactive kiosk framework. Used to run the OSL's datacenter kiosk. Built with Python, Django, Twisted, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Also gave a talk at OSBridge June 2010.

# Drupal Websites:

Collaborated on the design, development, installation, and configuration of osuosl.org, goscon.org, and co.polk.or.us, based on the Drupal PHP content management system.

# >>> Portland Art Museum, NW Film Center

Assistant Instructor, Digital Film Editor | July 2003 - July 2007

# Children's Animation Courses:

Taught students how to animate their own short films, and edited digital film for final class presentations, premiered at the Guild Theater in Portland.

# >>> Education

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# Oregon State University:

- B.S. in Computer Science, Sept. 2011

# Mt. Hood Community College

- A.S. in Computer Science, Sept. 2008
- A.S. in Mathematics, Sept. 2008

# >>> Conferences

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# Speaker:

- Open Source Bridge, June 2010 in Portland, OR: "Building Interactive Displays with Touchscreen 2.0" <a href="http://opensourcebridge.org/sessions/404">http://opensourcebridge.org/sessions/404</a>>

# Attendee:

- GOSCON (Government Open Source Conference), Oct. 2010 in Portland, OR
- Google I/O, June 2011 in San Francisco, CA